BRIDGET M. HASS

541.231.0303 | bridgethass@gmail.com

Summary

Skilled in developing open, reproducible workflows for remote sensing data processing and analysis. Experience developing and teaching open-source tutorials in Python Jupyter Notebooks and Google Earth Engine for working with aerial lidar and hyperspectral data.

Relevant Experience

2016 – Present National Ecological Observatory Network (NEON) Airborne Observation Platform (AOP)
Battelle Memorial Institute: Boulder CO

2018 - Present Remote Sensing Data Scientist

- Develop automated, version-controlled workflows for lidar processing and generating open access remote sensing (aerial lidar, hyperspectral, camera) data products
- Create and teach live-coding tutorials on reproducible workflows using NEON remote sensing data
- Create and maintain remote sensing data pipelines
- Lead field campaigns for lidar validation and hyperspectral radiometric calibration

2016-2018 Remote Sensing Technician Specialist

- Process remote sensing data from raw to higher level data products, perform QA/QC
- Conduct calibration processing and associated field work
- Update and maintain processing pipeline, prepare technical documentation
- 2012 2015 *Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant*, Oregon State University College of Earth, Ocean, and Atmospheric Science; Corvallis, OR
 - Thesis on subduction zone heat flow modeling for the International Ocean Drilling Program (IODP) Costa Rica Seismogenesis Project (CRISP). Published findings in G³ (Geochemistry, Geophysics, Geosystems)
 - Consulted on international marine oil exploration cruises; collected, processed, and analyzed marine heat flow data for use in models to locate offshore petroleum reservoirs
 - Taught undergraduate laboratory courses in geology, geophysics, and atmospheric science.
- 2011-2012 *Marine Geophysical Technician*, Scripps Institution of Oceanography, University of California San Diego; San Diego, CA
 - Assembled, maintained, repaired, and assisted with shipboard operations of marine geophysical instruments including multichannel seismic reflection, magnetometers, and echosounders on scientific research cruises

Relevant Experience, Continued

2010 Field Geophysicist, Dewhurst Group, LLC

- Conducted magnetotelluric (MT) surveys for geothermal energy exploration consulting company
- Generated daily field operation reports and mapped completed surveys
- Wrote an instruction manual for MT field methods

Education

2012-2015 M.S., Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR

- Degree in Earth, Ocean, and Atmospheric Science, Concentration in Marine Geophysics
- Research projects in seismology and heat flow

2007-2010 B.S., Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

- Degree in Science of Earth Systems
- Honors thesis on seismic receiver functions to map geothermal profile of New Mexico

Selected Open-Source Training

Oct 2020 Google Earth Engine for Ecology and Conservation – Organization for Tropical Studies

Feb-June 2020 Data Science Nanodegree – Udacity 4 month/160 hr training in Python to learn Data

Science principals including data pipelines, software engineering principles, machine

learning, and recommendation systems

Feb 2020 CyVerse Foundations for Open Science Skills – University of Arizona; week long

workshop on open science skills, version control, reproducible research

Jan 2017 Reproducible Science Curriculum Hackathon – Berkeley Institute for Data Science

Reproducible Research using Jupyter Notebooks

Workshops and Teaching

2020 - 2021 Instructor: CyVerse-NEON Airborne Observation Platform Workshop (Nov 2020 and Nov

2021) Open source tools in R, Python, and Google Earth Engine for working with NEON

AOP data in the CyVerse computing environment.

Webinar Co-Host: Bright Lights, Big Data (Feb 2021): Leverage NEON's Datasets and

Resources. https://cyverse.org/webinar-NEON

2017 & 2018 Developer & Instructor: Remote Sensing Data Institutes: Working with NEON AOP Remote

Sensing Data in Python. https://www.neonscience.org/resources/learning-

hub/workshops/neon-data-institute-2018-remote-sensing-reproducible-workflows

Links

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bridget-hass-63123691

GitHub: https://github.com/bridgethass